Hello cruel world.
Cruella is a comedy, crime, adventure film directed by Craig Gillespie.
In 1970s London amidst the punk rock revolution, a young grifter named
Estella is determined to make a name for herself with her designs.
She befriends a pair of young thieves who appreciate her appetite for mischief, and
together they are able to build a life for themselves on the London streets.
One day, Estella’s flair for fashion catches the eye of the Baroness von Hellman, a
fashion legend who is devastatingly chic and terrifyingly haute.
But their relationship sets in motion a course of events and revelations that will cause Estella to
embrace her wicked side and become the raucous, fashionable and revenge-bent Cruella.
Estella / Cruella, played by Emma Stone.
The Baroness, played by Emma Thompson.
Jasper, played by Joel Fry.
Horace, played by Paul Walter Hauser.
Artie, played by John McCrea.
Catherine / Maid, played by Emily Beecham.
Cruella is a 2021 American crime comedy-drama film directed by Craig Gillespie from a screenplay by Dana
Fox and Tony McNamara, and a story by Aline Brosh McKenna, Kelly Marcel, and Steve Zissis.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures, Marc Platt Productions, and Gunn Films, it is based on Dodie Smith's 1956 novel The Hundred
and One Dalmatians, serving as a backstory and an alternative origin story for its antagonist, Cruella de Vil.
It is also the third live-action adaptation in the 101 Dalmatians franchise.
The film stars Emma Stone as the title character, with Emma Thompson, Joel Fry, Paul Walter
Hauser, Emily Beecham, Kirby Howell-Baptiste, and Mark Strong in supporting roles.
Set in London during the punk rock movement of the 1970s, the film follows Estella Miller, an aspiring fashion designer, as she
explores the path that leads her to become a notorious up-and-coming fashion designer known as Cruella de Vil.
In 2013, Disney announced the film's development with Andrew Gunn as a producer.
Stone was cast in 2016 and also serves as an executive producer on the film alongside Glenn Close, who portrayed
Cruella in the previous live-action adaptations, 101 Dalmatians (1996) and 102 Dalmatians (2000).
Principal photography took place in England between August
and November 2019 with a $100 million budget.
Cruella premiered in Los Angeles on May 18, 2021, in the first major
red carpet event since the COVID-19 pandemic began.
It was released in the United States theatrically by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures and simultaneously available on Disney+ with
its Premier Access feature on May 28, to generally positive reviews from critics and grossed over $233 million worldwide.
The film earned two nominations at the 94th Academy Awards, including
Best Makeup and Hairstyling, winning Best Costume Design.
It was also nominated in the former category and won in the latter at the 27th Critics' Choice Awards and 75th British Academy Film
Awards, while Stone was nominated for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy at the 79th Golden Globe Awards.
A sequel is in development, with Stone set to reprise her role.
The film explores themes of 1970s, anti hero,
villain, punk rock, fashion designer.
The tone is lighthearted.